Otto Sternoff Beyer Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Otto Sternoff Beyer Papers 1905-1951 1929-1941
MSS12633
Beyer, Otto Sternoff, 1886-1948
45,000 items
129 containers plus 5 oversize
53 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Engineer, economist, and labor consultant. Correspondence, speech and article file, subject files, scrapbooks, and other papers relating to Beyer's career as an engineer and economist in industry and government.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Beyer, Clara M. (Clara Mortenson). Clara M. Beyer papers.; Beyer, Otto Sternoff, 1886-1948.; Green, William, 1870-1952--Correspondence.; Lilienthal, David Eli, 1899-1981--Correspondence.; Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Tobin, James, 1918-2002--Correspondence.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972--Correspondence.
Organizations
Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company.; Canadian National Railways.; Tennessee Valley Authority.; United States. Bonneville Power Administration.; United States. Department of Labor.; United States. National Mediation Board.
Subjects
Electric utilities--Northwest, Pacific.; Electric utilities--Tennessee River Valley.; Industrial relations.; Labor unions.; Railroads--Canada.; Railroads--Employees--Labor unions.; Railroads--United States.; Strikes and lockouts.; Unemployment.; Wages.
Occupations
Economists.; Engineers.; Labor consultants.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Otto Sternoff Beyer, economist, engineer and labor consultant, were given to the Library of Congress by Clara M. Beyer in 1955 and 1965. Additional material was transferred from the Department of Labor in 1962 and 1988.
Access and Restrictions
The Beyer Papers of are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1886, 18 Sept. Born, Woodbridge, N.J.
1907 Graduate in mechanical engineering, Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, N.J.
1907 1908 Estimator and assistant to superintendent of rolling mill, Midvale Steel Co., Philadelphia, Pa.
1907 1910 Graduate work, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pa.
1908 1911 Special apprentice, Motive Power and Car Departments, Erie Railroad Co., New York
1911 1912 Inspector of materials, Shop and Motive Power, Erie Railroad Co.
1912 1913 Engineer of Motive Power and Operation, Office of Assistant Vice President, Rock Island Lines, Chicago, Ill.
1913 1916 General foreman, Second District Shops, Rock Island Lines, Horton, Kans.
1916 1917 Research engineer, Engineering Experiment Station, Department of Railway Engineering, and instructor in Railway mechanical engineering
1917 1920 Captain, United States Army, served in organization of United States Army School of Aeronautics, Urbana, Ill. Director, Arsenal Orders Section, Army Ordnance Department
1920 Married Clara Mortenson
1920 1933 Consulting engineer with several railway systems and industrial companies in developing labor-management cooperative programs, among them the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Co. and Canadian National Railways
1933 1935 Director, Section of Labor Relations, Federal Coordinator of Transportation
1935 1948 Labor relations consultant, Tennessee Valley Authority
1936 1942 Member, National Mediation Board, chairman in 1937 and 1940
1942 1944 Director, Division of Transport Personnel, Office of Defense Transportation
1943 1944 Member, War Manpower Commission
1944 Consultant, Bonneville Power Administration, United States Maritime Commission, Alaska Railroad, and Department of Interior Special lecturer, George Washington University, Washington, D.C.
1948, 8 Dec. Died
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Otto Sternoff Beyer (1886-1948) consist of personal and professional correspondence, memoranda, reports, speeches and articles, charts, and other papers, as well as scrapbooks of clippings relating mainly to his professional career. The papers span the years 1905-1951, but bulk largest from 1929 to 1941. The collection is organized into eleven series: General Correspondence, Subject File, General Railroad File, Canadian National Railways, Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, Tennessee Valley Authority, Bonneville Power Administration, Speech and Article File, Scrapbooks, Addition, and Oversize.
During Beyer's military service in World War I, he developed a program of union-management cooperation in army arsenals. Thereafter, he served as consulting engineer to unions and management in various industrial concerns and in railway systems such as the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company and the Canadian National Railways, acquiring a reputation as a leader in the improvement of labor-management relations. From 1933 to 1948, Beyer held a number of posts in the federal government. His papers document his widespread activities in considerable detail, including labor-management cooperation in the field of railway transportation, his connection with federal agencies, and work in the area of labor relations, unions, wages, strikes, and unemployment.
An Addition series contains biographical material and letters of condolence from Harry S. Truman, James Tobin, and others government officials. The article file in the Addition contains Beyer's notes on a projected history of railroad personnel, in which he was encouraged by Professor Sumner Slichter of Harvard. The subject file contains background material on his various positions with railroads, the Tennessee Valley Authority, and the National Mediation Board during World War II. There is also material pertaining to Clara M. Beyer consisting of family correspondence and photographs, White House invitations, and material pertaining to her own position in the Labor Department.
Correspondents in the Addition include Franklin D. Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt, Harry S. Truman, David E. Lilienthal, Frances Perkins and William Green of the American Federation of Labor.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in eleven series:
General Correspondence, 1929-1947
Subject File, 1905-1947
General Railroad File, 1915-1948
Canadian National Railways, 1921-1948
Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, 1921-1942
Tennessee Valley Authority, 1933-1948
Bonneville Power Administration, 1940-1947
Speech and Article File, 1919-1947
Scrapbooks, 1909-1943
Addition, 1933-1951
Oversize, 1923-1943
Container List
- General Correspondence, 1929-1947 (Box 1-8)
  Letters sent and received with attached and related matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person.
  - Alberty, Harry, 1933-1936 (Box 1)
  - "A" miscellaneous, 1937-1941
  - Bergen, Harold B., 1937
  - Beyer, Donald, 1935-1947 See also Container 6, Porter, John
  - Beyer, Edward S., 1947
  - Beyer, Morten, 1940
  - Beyer, Otto, letters of congratulations, 1935-1939
  - Beyer, Mrs. Otto (Clara M. Beyer), 1947
  - Beyer, Richard, 1940-1941, 1947 See also Container 6, Porter, John
  - Brissenten, Paul F., 1939-1941
  - Brown, J. Douglas, 1933-1942
  - Bruere, Henry, 1937-1941
  - "B" miscellaneous, 1935-1942
  - Budd, Ralph C., 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - Carmody, John M., 1938-1941 (Box 3)
  - Carroll, Tom, 1947
  - Case, Harry L., 1946-1947
  - Cooke, Morris L., 1938-1941
  - Cranmer, Richard H., 1933-1940
  - Craven, Leslie, 1933-1941
  - "C" miscellaneous, 1929-1940
  - Dale, Earnest, 1946-1947
  - Dimock, Marshall E., 1935-1941
  - "D" miscellaneous, 1916-1941
  - Eastman, Joseph B., 1933-1944
  - Eliel, Paul, 1937-1941
  - Elderton, A., 1933-1941
  - Fisher, H.H., 1916
  - Free, Lloyd A., 1947
  - Gant, George P., 1942-1944
  - Gardiener, Emily, 1947
  - Goodrich, Carter, 1928-1935
  - Green, Robert F., 1947
  - "G" miscellaneous, 1916-1941
  - Hardy, John K., regarding "Protection of Aircraft Against Ice," 1946-1947 (Box 4)
  - Harrison, George M., 1947
  - Harrison, Wilton, 1931-1939
  - Hawkins, Everett D., 1938-1941
  - Hay, Charles M., 1937-1942
  - Hedges, Marion, 1942-1947
  - Heron, Alexander R., 1940
  - Hersey, R. B., 1941
  - Hobart, James L., 1939
  - Hood, J. M., 1937-1941
  - Hook, C. R., Jr., 1947
  - Hornberger, Ludwig M., 1940-1942
  - Husted, A. S., 1916
  - "H-I" miscellaneous, 1931-1943
  - James, Gorton, 1929
  - Jewell, B. M., 1933-1939
  - Johnson, Eleanor, 1947
  - "J" miscellaneous, 1916-1944
  - Kaplan, H. Eliot, 1946-1947 (Box 5)
  - Keezer, Dexter M., 1937-1941
  - King, Judson, 1939-1941
  - Klemmer, Harvey, 1947
  - "K" miscellaneous, 1931-1943
  - Lane, Chester T., 1947
  - Lang, Ray W., 1934-1935
  - Lasting, May, 1947
  - Latimer, Murray, 1934-1941
  - Leiserson, William M., 1934-1938
  - Lubin, Isadore, 1937-1938
  - Lum, Merrett, 1936-1940
  - Lyman, Carson F., 1947
  - "L" miscellaneous, 1931-1944
  - McClees, E. J., 1939
  - "Mc" miscellaneous, 1933-1941
  - Marlett, Loring, 1946-1947
  - Mars, Hans, 1932-1933
  - Melnikow, H. P., 1936-1940
  - Metcalf, Henry C., 1930-1937
  - Miller, Frieda, 1941-1942
  - Millis, H. A., 1939-1940
  - Morley, Felix, 1935-1936
  - Murrell, Garland, 1947
  - "M" miscellaneous, 1934-1943 (Box 6)
  - Nau, Carlton L., 1947
  - Newdick, Edwin, 1932-1934
  - "N" miscellaneous, 1933-1943
  - Oakey, Margaret C., 1940-1941
  - Ogburn, Charlton, 1934-1941
  - "O" miscellaneous, 1936-1942
  - Pickering, George, 1939-1940
  - Porter, John, 1935-1941
  - Pusey, Merlo, 1947
  - "P" miscellaneous, 1937-1943
  - "Q" miscellaneous, 1936-1940 (Box 7)
  - Richberg, Donald R., 1929-1942
  - "R" miscellaneous, 1935-1941
  - Schmidt, Edward G., 1915-1940
  - Sekerak, Emil E., 1939-1942
  - Shultz, E. B., 1946-1947
  - Soule, George, 1930-1935
  - Spero, Sterling D., 1947
  - Stark, Louis, 1941
  - Starzenski, Victor, 1947
  - Stengle, Charles I., 1947
  - Stern, Max, 1947
  - Stocking, George W., 1937-1940
  - Swacker, Frank M., 1936-1940
  - "S" miscellaneous, 1930-1946
  - Tallon, Robert J., 1933-1940
  - "T" miscellaneous, 1932-1942
  - "U" miscellaneous, 1930-1943 (Box 8)
  - Van Sant, Robert M., 1936-1942
  - Vaughn, L. D., 1936
  - "V" miscellaneous, 1929-1942
  - Watkins, Ralph J., 1940-1941
  - Westbrook, W. Harry, 1935-1939
  - Wiley, Henry A., 1934-1936
  - Williams, Whiting, 1930-1942
  - Williard, Daniel, 1923-1941
  - Wilmotte, Raymond, 1933-1936
  - Woll, Matthew, 1934-1940
  - Wolman, Leo, 1933-1937
  - Wood, L. A., 1929-1937
  - Woodward, Thomas M., 1938-1939
  - Wright, Roy V., 1929-1936
  - "W" miscellaneous, 1932-1943
  - Young, Robert R., 1947
  - "X-Z" miscellaneous, 1939-1941
- Subject File, 1905-1947 (Box 9-47)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, notes, reports, charts, articles, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, organization, or type of material.
  - Adjustment boards, circa 1920-1941 (Box 9)
  - Air transport industry, circa 1937-1939
  - Air transportation, "Current Labor Problems in Scheduled Air Transportation," circa 1933
  - Airline Mechanics Association, circa 1934-1941
  - Airline Pilots' Association, circa 1938-1945
  - Airline pilots' standards, international, circa 1945
  - Airlines, circa 1942; 1946-1947
  - Alaska labor policy statement, distribution of, circa 1947 (Box 10)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, circa 1925-1938
  - American Airlines, Inc., circa 1937-1941
  - American Association for Labor Legislation, circa 1938-1941
  - American Engineering Council, circa 1931-1940
  - American Federation of Labor, circa 1925-1940
    - Committee on Education
    - Monthly survey of business
      - circa 1929-1935
      - circa 1936-1939
  - American Public Power Association, circa 1947
  - American University, Washington, D.C.
    - General, 1940-1941
    - Proposed air transport courses, circa 1941-1942
  - Anthracite coal wage case, circa 1933
  - Applications for employment, circa 1932-1947 (Box 11)
  - Apprentice training, circa 1929-1942
  - Arsenals, circa 1917-1920
  - Atomic information and Atomic Energy Commission, circa 1946-1947
  - Attorney General's Committee on Administrative Procedure, report, circa 1941
  - Baltimore Typographical Union, circa 1932-1933
  - Bibliography, Beyer
  - British industrial relations (Box 12)
  - Building trades, circa 1928-1947
  - Bus transportation, circa 1946
  - Business chart, business booms, and depressions, circa 1946-1947
  - Cafeteria strike, circa 1947
  - Canadian civil service, circa 1945-1947
  - Central Statistical Board, circa 1934-1939
  - Certification List, 1937
  - "Changes in Spirit, Management," circa 1924-1930
  - Chicago Association of Commerce, Chicago, Ill., circa 1947
  - Chimney construction, circa 1925-1927
  - Civil Aeronautics Authority, circa 1938-1939
  - Civil liberties, circa 1937-1939
  - Civil service assembly
    - circa 1947-1948
    - Committee on Employee Relations, circa 1936-1940 (Box 13)
  - Civil Service Committee, Conference of Employee Relations and Hearings of Grievances, circa 1940
  - Civil service mediation, circa 1939
  - Coal, circa 1946-1947
  - Colgate University, Hamilton, N.Y., 1945
  - Collective bargaining, circa 1937-1947
  - Columbia Power Authority, circa 1941
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations, circa 1939
  - Cooperation of trade unions with employers, 1928
  - Cooperative businesses, circa 1937-1938
  - Cooperative Committee in Action,, circa 1927 (Box 14)
  - Cooperative Committee of the Democratic Party, circa 1937-1940
  - Cooperative survey, background
    - circa 1912-1920
    - circa 1921-1924
    - circa 1924-1930
    - circa 1924-1930 (Box 15)
    - circa 1924-1931
  - Cosmos Club, Washington, D. C. circa 1946-1947
  - Democratic National Committee, circa 1937-1941
  - Dismissal compensation data
    - circa 1933-1936
    - circa 1935-1936 (Box 16)
  - District of Columbia Society of Civil Engineers, circa 1940
  - Economic trends, circa 1937-1939
  - Electrical Guild of North America, circa 1931
  - Employee Relations Committee
    - Council of Personnel
    - Administration, circa 1945-1946
  - Employee relations
    - Including relations with labor unions, circa 1947
    - Officer duties
    - Program federal service, circa 1946-1947
  - Employer opinions, circa 1941-1946
  - Engineer in society, status of, circa 1920-1921
  - Fair labor standards, Black-Connery Bill, circa 1937-1938 (Box 17)
  - Federal coordinator of transportation
    - Rules survey, circa 1934
    - Statements, circa 1934
  - Federal labor relations policy in industry, circa 1941-1945
  - Foreign Economic Administration, Transportation and Communications Division, circa 1945 (Box 18)
  - Full Fashioned Hosiery Manufacturers of America, circa 1931
  - Garment workers, circa 1947
  - George Washington University, Washington, D.C., circa 1945
  - Great Valley Anthracite Corp., circa 1931-1933
  - Group Health Association, Inc., circa 1937-1938
  - Group insurance, circa 1934
  - Hart, Schaffner and Marx, labor relations, circa 1916-1926
  - Harvard Business School, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - circa 1930-1942
    - circa 1945 (Box 19)
    - Bushelman's arbitration case, circa 1941
    - Library, circa 1934
  - Highlander Folk School, circa 1947
  - Howard Smith Paper Mills, Cornwall, Ontario, circa 1946
  - Human Events, weekly analysis, circa 1945-1947
  - Incentives in industry, circa 1918-1920
  - Industrial democracy, circa 1920
  - Industrial relations, George Cusick article, 1932
  - Industrial safety, circa 1931
  - Inland Waterways Cooperation
    - circa 1938
    - circa 1947
  - Institute of Management Policy meeting, 11 June 1940
  - International Association of Machinists, circa 1924-1940
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, circa 1929-1938
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen, etc., circa 1938 (Box 20)
  - International Management Institute, 1927, 1938
  - Interstate Commerce Commission, transportation statistics, circa 1947
  - Kaiser Co.
  - Kiplinger Letter, circa 1941-1945
  - Konsum, Inc., circa 1938-1946
  - Labor and the war, circa 1943-1944
  - Labor Bureau, Inc., circa 1929-1940
  - Labor Disputes Act, circa 1934-1935
  - Labor, miscellaneous
    - circa 1932-1948
    - circa 1932-1948 (Box 21)
  - Labor, Vinson Bill, 1941
  - Labor Laws, European countries, circa 1937-1938
  - Labor Management Conference, White House
    - Proceedings, 1942
    - Public Hearings Committee, 1945
    - Legislation, circa 1940; 1946-1947
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1944-1947 (Box 22)
    - Publications, circa 1946-1947
  - Labor relations
    - Courses in universities, circa 1941-1945
    - Great Britain, circa 1938 (Box 23)
    - Legislation
      - Federal, circa 1947
      - State, circa 1937
    - Miscellaneous
      - circa 1914-1928
      - circa 1926-1944
      - circa 1945-1948 (Box 24)
    - Sweden, circa 1938-1939
  - Labor unions
    - circa 1923-1947
    - circa 1946-1947
    - Statisticians Conference, 1934
  - Legal opinions, circa 1944
  - Lithographers' unions publications
  - Logan Bill, 1939
  - Louden Machinery Co., circa 1937-1938
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast, circa 1936
  - Maritime Labor, proposed legislation, circa 1934-1937
  - Masters, Mates and Pilots of America, circa 1923-1938 (Box 25)
  - Mine workers, circa 1945-1947
  - Minimum Wage Board, Manufacturing and Wholesale Merchandising, circa 1942-1948
  - Miscellaneous
  - Missouri River Basin, circa 1944-1945
  - Missouri Valley Development, Trades and Labor Council, circa 1947
  - Motor carrier data, circa 1935
  - National Association of Die Casting Workers (Box 26)
  - National Defense Management Conference for Industry and Government, circa 1940
  - National Economic and Social Planning Association, circa 1934-1939
  - National income, circa 1929-1932
  - National Industrial Conference Board, circa 1938-1940
  - National Labor Relations Board, congressional investigation, circa 1939-1940
  - National Labor Relations Board
    - Decisions, circa 1939-1940
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1934-1942
    - Speeches by others, circa 1937-1939
  - National Mediation Board (Box 27)
    - Airlines, circa 1946
    - Annual leave, circa 1936-1938
    - Case assignments, circa 1936-1939
    - Cases, miscellaneous, circa 1932-1942
    - Cases, monthly statements, circa 1936-1942
    - Determination of craft or class, circa 1938-1942
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1933-1940; 1947
    - Referees, circa 1933-1941 (Box 28)
    - Reports, circa 1936-1941
    - Reports, annual, circa 1935-1939
    - Statement of activities, circa 1940
  - National Policy Committee, circa 1940-1942
  - National Recovery Administration, circa 1933-1934
  - National Research Council, circa 1941
  - National Sugar Manufacturing Co., circa 1940 (Box 29)
  - Naumkeag Steam Cotton Co.
    - circa 1928-1930
    - circa 1931-1932
  - New York printing trades, journeyman requirements, circa 1928
  - New York, N.Y., subway, circa 1946
  - Nicholson Thermic Syphons Co., circa 1931-1934
  - Norris-LaGuardia Anti-Injunction Act, circa 1932
  - Office of Defense Transportation
    - Division of Personnel
      - circa 1943
      - Orientation
    - Course, circa 1943
    - Beyer resignation from, Apr.-May 1944 (Box 30)
  - Office of Stabilization Administrator, circa 1946
  - Pan-American Airways, circa 1947
  - Pension legislation and plans, circa 1932-1933
  - Personnel administration, circa 1944-1948
  - Policy Holders' Service Bureau, circa 1923
  - Postwar planning activities
    - circa 1933-1946
    - circa 1944-1945
    - circa 1944-1945 (Box 31)
  - Power projects, circa 1938-1944
  - Princeton University, Industrial Relations Section, Princeton, N.J., circa 1930
  - Productivity in industry, circa 1935; 1947-1948
  - Progressive conference, 1931
  - Public health, circa 1927-1938
  - Public utilities, circa 1946
  - Public works, circa 1946
  - Radio material, circa 1936-1937
  - Reconstruction Finance Corp., circa 1933-1935
  - Remington Rand, circa 1930-1931
  - "Robots or Men," by H. Dubreuil
  - Rock Island Arsenal, Rock, Ill., circa 1919-1920; 1943 (Box 32)
  - Rocky Mountain Fuel Co., circa 1930-1933
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., speeches, circa 1938
  - Round table discussion exploring factors involved in reemployment of labor and capital, circa 1940
  - St. Lawrence River Project
  - Scientific management, circa 1922-1937
  - Seagoing personnel, circa 1942-1945
  - Shipbuilding Stabilization Committee, circa 1945
  - Shorter work day, circa 1924-1937 (Box 33)
  - Shorter work week, and vacation with pay
    - General correspondence, circa 1930-1932
    - General data, circa 1921-1930
  - Shorter work week, outline prepared for establishment (Box 34)
  - Siemund Wenzel Electric Welding Co., circa 1911-1913
  - Slichter, Sumner, articles, circa 1942
  - Social Science Research Council, survey of research in field of industrial relations, circa 1928
  - Social survey, Labor Management Committee, circa 1946
  - Society for Personnel Administration, circa 1946-1947
  - Society for the Advancement of Management, circa 1932-1941
  - Statistical Bureau, organization, circa 1930
  - Steel Workers Organizing Committee, circa 1939-1941
  - Stevens Economic Conference, 1939
  - Stevens Institute, Hoboken, N.J. (Box 35)
    - Analysis of coal
    - Design notebook
    - Electrical engineering notes
    - Electrical laboratory notes, circa 1905-1907
    - Laboratory physics
    - Lecture notes (Box 36)
    - Physics notebook
  - "Stretchout," circa 1934 (Box 37)
  - Strikes, circa 1934-1947
    - Steel, circa 1947
    - Teachers, circa 1946-1947
    - Telephone, circa 1947
    - Western Union co., circa 1947
  - Supervisory employees
    - circa 1947
    - Labor standards in, circa 1937-1938
  - Unemployment
    - circa 1930-1933
    - circa 1933-1937
  - Union-management cooperation (Box 38)
    - circa 1919-1924
    - circa 1919-1929
    - Articles, reports, etc., circa 1925-1929
    - Bibliography
    - General statements, circa 1924-1931
    - In America, circa 1928
    - Publications
  - Unions (Box 39)
    - Changes in spirit
    - Printing press assistants local
    - Trade union policies and technological change, circa 1939
    - Trade union responsibility, circa 1931-1937
  - United States
    - Employment service
      - circa 1933-1937
      - circa 1933-1936 (Box 40)
      - circa 1936-1939
      - circa 1933-1937
    - Government (Box 41)
      - Grievance procedures
        - circa 1945-1946
        - circa 1946
      - Labor policy, circa 1946-1947
      - Reorganization, circa 1937
      - Training programs, circa 1945-1947
      - Union problems, circa 1935
    - Interior Department
      - Labor relations policy, circa 1945
      - Personnel organization charts, circa 1947
      - Proposed labor-management policy
        - 1946-1948
        - 1946-1948 (Box 42)
    - Labor Department, circa 1933-1941
    - Maritime Commission
      - Account, circa 1945-1946
      - Increased Rates from, to, and within Alaska, circa 1945, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Navy Department, policy, circa 1944-1946
    - War Department, employment policy, circa 1944
  - University of Michigan, Bureau of Industrial Relations, Ann Arbor, Mich., circa 1938
  - Upholstery Weavers and Workers Union, circa 1931-1932
  - Veterans' Administration policy, circa 1946 (Box 44)
  - Vocational guidance, circa 1935
  - Wage adjustment, circa 1921-1946
  - Wage payment plans, etc., circa 1930-1932
  - Wage statistics
    - Handbook, circa 1932-1937
    - Inquiries, circa 1921
    - Interstate Commerce Commission, circa 1929-1932 (Box 45)
  - Wages, automobile industry, circa 1945-1947